Oh , that 's a big fella .
Whoa !
- Looks great . - Thank you .
- Happy vacation , honey . - Ooh .
Manchurian tung oil . Where did you get this ?
Helen got it for me in Oslo .
Well , there 's enough here to do the whole table and the bureau .
Hmm .
I wonder what this could be .
- Oh , honey , you got it . Thank you . - Enough there to do the entire guest room .
I 'm so glad we 're spending our vacation at home .
- I 'm gonna get started right away . - Well , hey , where are you going ?
[ GIGGLES ]
[ PHONE RINGING ]
- I 'll get it . - Be my guest .
I 'll just get the ...
[ LAUGHS ]
- Maybe you should get it . - I 'll go .
Okay . No !
[ LAUGHS ]
[ CAR DRIVING UP ON GRAVEL ]
[ CAR HORN HONKS ]
Oh , no .
Ugh , Jane .
It 's your turn , honey .
- Good luck . - Thanks .
- Hi , Barbara . - Hi .
Glad I caught you . Heard you were on vacation .
That 's right . Complete vacation .
- Honey , today I 'm $ 260,000 . - No , Jane .
- It 's 6 : 45 in the morning . - This offer is real .
From a man in New York City who only saw a photograph .
Jane , don 't send people photos of our house .
He wants to bring the wife and family up here for some peace and quiet .
That 's exactly what we 're looking for .
But , Barbara , this house is too big for you .
It really ought to be for a couple with a family , you know ... ?
Oh , pumpkin , I didn 't mean anything . It 's just that this house is too big .
- I 'll see you in a few weeks . Okay ? - Okay .
- All right . - Think about it .
BARBARA : Take care .
[ HARRY BELAFONTE 'S " MAN SMART , WOMA SMARTER " PLAYING ]
Boo !
- I was just telling Barbara about this offer ... - No , Jane .
Adam .
[ MUSIC STOPS ]
Barbara , come with me down to the store .
- What for ? - I need a new brush for this tung oil .
- And I want to get a part for the model . - Well , you just run in , okay ?
ADAM : Two weeks at home . The perfect vacation .
BARBARA : Jane says we should sell the house to someone with a family .
Well , I don 't think that it 's any of Jane 's business .
Besides , we could try again on this vacation , you know .
Oh , really ? What are you saying ?
ADAM : How are you doing , Ernie ? ERNIE : Hi , how are you ?
Morning , Adam .
- Need a haircut before your vacation ? - No , thanks , Bill .
- How 's the model coming ? - Oh , it 's great .
You know , you said Bozman built that foundation in 1835 . But his grandson ...
He got hair right down to his goddamn shoulders .
He says to me , " Just trim it a little . "
- I took the scissors to him so fast ... - See you later , huh , Bill ?
BILL : Right .
This is gonna be great .
Are you sure you wouldn 't rather go to Jamaica or some place like that ?
- No way . There 's no place like home . - Hey , look out for that ... !
[ BARBARA SCREAMS ]
[ ADAM GROANS ]
[ BOTH SCREAMING ]
[ CUCKOOING ]
BARBARA : Perfect start to our vacation .
Well , you 'll feel better when you 're dry , honey .
BARBARA : That fire wasn 't burning when we left .
- How 's your arm ? - I don 't know . It feels frozen .
[ GASPS ]
I 'll make some coffee and you get wood for the fire .
Maybe we should just take things extra slow .
Do you remember how we got back up here ?
I 'm gonna go back down to the bridge and retrace our steps .
[ GROWLING NEARBY ]
- You saved my ... - Two hours .
- Barbara , you are not gonna believe ... What ? - That 's how long you were gone .
- What is going on ? - I have to show you something .
Look .
There 's that .
And there 's that .
- " Handbook for the Recently Diseased . " - Deceased .
" Deceased . "
I don 't know where it came from . Look at the publisher .
" Handbook for the Recently Deceased Press . "
You know what ? I don 't think we survived the crash .
I hate this .
Just ... Can you give me the basics ?
Well , this book isn 't arranged that way . What do you wanna know ?
Well , why did you disappear when you stepped off the porch ?
Are we halfway to heaven , are we halfway to hell ?
And how long is this gonna last ?
I don 't see anything about heaven or hell .
This book reads like stereo instructions . Listen to this :
" Geographical and Temporal Perimeters .
Functional perimeters vary from manifestation to manifestation . "
Oh , this is gonna take some time , honey .
[ BARBARA MOANS ]
[ MAN HUMMING ]
Damn sandworms . Thirteen percent , huh ?
Well , I better find a job . Let 's see . Business section .
Ooh-la-la .
What do we got here ? The Maitlands , huh ?
[ CHUCKLES ]
Cute couple . Look nice and stupid too .
[ LAUGHS ]
I wish I had a better view of the cemetery from here .
I can 't tell which is the best placement for us .
[ SPUTTERS ]
Cabin fever , hon ?
Well , I can 't clean anything properly .
The vacuum 's out in the garage and we can 't leave the house .
Why don 't they tell us something ? Where are all the other dead people ?
Why is it just you and me ?
Maybe this is heaven .
In heaven there wouldn 't be dust on everything .
[ CAR DOOR CLOSES ]
ADAM : It 's Jane .
BARBARA : God , what 's she doing here ? - I don 't know . Hey , Jane , up here . Jane .
- Can 't see you , right ? - Uh-uh .
In the book , rule number two : " The living usually won 't see the dead . "
- Won 't or can 't ? - It just says " won 't . "
God , this book is so stupid . I can 't understand anything in there .
Barb , honey
we 're dead .
I don 't think we have very much to worry about anymore .
[ RUMBLING ]
BARBARA : Aah !
[ BANGING DOWNSTAIRS ]
MAN 1 : Ah , this is great . This is just what the doctor ordered .
Sorry , ma 'am .
Delia Deetz , welcome home .
Charles .
It 's okay , there 's no damage . Look , see ? It 's okay .
Good , sturdy , country craftsmanship .
And look at that kitchen .
You 're finally gonna be able to cook a decent meal .
Come and have a look .
A little gasoline . Blowtorch . No problem .
Excuse me . Down we go .
CHARLES : We 'll have to rip out all the plumbing .
But other than that , it 's perfect . Just perfect .
- What do you think , honey ? - Delia hates it .
I could live here .
Careful . That 's my sculpture .
I don 't mean " my " as in " I bought it . " I mean I made it . It 's my sculpture .
Put it on the table .
Ten minutes . I 'm already perfectly at ease .
It 's perfect .
[ MAN 2 GRUNTING ]
MAN 2 : Help ! - It 's Otho .
CHARLES : Otho , why don 't you just come in the front ?
It 's bad luck .
Otho , you left the city for me . I am so happy .
Of course you are .
- Delia . - You 're right .
- Let 's get one thing straight . - You 're right .
- We 're here to enjoy the country setting ... - Mm-hm .
- ... not to trash the place . - You 're right .
OTHO : Charles , you 're lucky the yuppies are buying condos
so you can afford what I 'm going to have to do to this place .
Otho , I 'm here to relax and clip coupons , and , damn it , I mean to do it .
Then go do it quietly , dear , and let Otho and I think .
OTHO : Is the rest of the house as bad as this ?
Is this a punishment or something ?
What are we gonna do ?
We 're not completely helpless , Barbara .
I 've been reading that book and there 's a word for people in our situation .
Ghosts .
OTHO : Delia , let 's get this show on the road .
We 're dealing with negative entertainment potential .
I mean , there 's absolutely no organic flow-through .
I noticed that too . It 's like a giant ant farm .
- What ? - I thought I saw something .
OTHO : You 've read my mind .
- I did ? - So few clients are able to read my mind .
They 're just not open to the experience .
Hmm .
[ GASPS ]
[ SCREAMS ]
My God .
We just have to pray the other closets are bigger than this one .
Ooh , look .
Ozzie and Harriet .
Ugh .
- What happened to these people ? - They died .
Oh , look , an indoor outhouse .
- Otho . - Viridian .
Viridian . Now , why do I know that name ?
Blue-green .
Hydrated chromic oxide .
Remember , I 'm schooled in chemistry . I was a hair analyst .
- What ? - Briefly .
Yuck . Deliver me from L.L.Bean .
- Boo ! - Aah !
I know what you two are up to and you 're not gonna get away with it .
Oh , honey , this is not working out at all .
Charles , I will not stop living and breathing art just because you need to relax .
Ha .
DELIA : I 'm here . I will live with you in this hellhole .
But I must express myself . If you don 't let me gut out this house
and make it my own , I will go insane and I will take you with me !
Yeah . Well , you know , maybe the house could use a little remodeling .
Uh , but why don 't you just leave this room alone , okay ?
Okay .
I 'm gonna get her .
So ?
Once you cover up the wallpaper , knock down a few walls
this place might just be livable .
- What 's on the third floor ? - Attic space .
Oh , I forgot to lock the attic door .
- Did you feel something ? - When ?
[ LOCK CLICKS ]
[ DOORKNOB RATTLES ]
- You don 't have a key ? - Maybe Charles does .
I have a feeling there 's something very interesting behind this door .
Yeah , ghosts of the people who died in this house , and they want us out of here .
So let 's do them a favor .
My God , that was close .
BARBARA : I cannot watch this .
What 's the good of being a ghost if you can 't frighten people away ?
- Honey . - No , I 'm not putting up with this .
[ SCREAMS ]
- Barbara , you don 't know what 's out there . - I don 't care .
ADAM : Barbara !
BARBARA : Adam .
- Adam ? - Barbara .
BARBARA : Adam !
- Adam . Oh , help . - Barbara .
Help , I 'm getting all yellow .
[ GROWLING NEARBY ]
[ ROARS ]
[ GROWLING ]
[ WHIMPERS ]
Adam !
Oh , Adam .
We 're trapped in this house with those people .
I can 't believe we 're eating Cantonese . Is there no Sichuan up here ?
Plan to have a stroke from the amount of MSG that 's in this food .
This is our first meal in this house
so why don 't we all do our little private parts to make it a pleasant one ?
Don 't bait your mother , pumpkin .
Soon as we get settled , we 'll build you a darkroom in the basement , okay ?
My whole life is a darkroom .
One big dark room .
So you were miserable in New York City
and now you 're going to be miserable out here in the sticks .
At least someone 's life hasn 't been upheaved .
I 'm perfectly happy here . Those people in New York
they just don 't know what they 're missing .
You know , we could become The Summer Art Center of New York .
I could start sculpting again . I 'm only truly happy when I 'm sculpting .
That 's a very good idea . That 'll be , um , ahem , very time-consuming .
First the house . Otho and I have some great plans .
I think we should keep it the way it is .
Good idea .
Furniture truck is coming . We 're gonna have to decide what goes and what stays .
Everything goes , along with whatever 's in the attic .
Put it up . Come on .
Careful .
You see , if you tell me what you do I 'll tell you why my husband will fire you .
- Isn 't there an index or something ? - No , nothing .
All right , now .
What 's this ?
DELIA : No , no , I 'm sorry . That does not go there .
Do you know where that 's going ? Did anyone tell you where to ... ?
Why are there only three sculptures ? There were four sculptures here .
Where 's the fourth sculpture ? No !
No , what are you doing ?
Excuse me . Put it down .
" Betelgeuse , the bio-exorcist . Troubled by the living ?
Is death a problem and not the solution ? Unhappy with eternity ?
Having difficulty adjusting ? Call Betelgeuse . "
[ CRASHING OUTSIDE ]
DELIA : Put it down . - Betelgeu ... Betel ...
That 's it ? There 's no number or instructions ?
Nothing . The " bio-exorcist . " I don 't get it .
[ CRASHING OUTSIDE ]
DELIA : Would you put that down ? - Straight back .
DELIA : Why is that still up there ?
Why don 't you guys take a break for about half an hour , okay ?
MAN : Uh-huh .
Jesus Christ !
DELIA : What are you doing ? Put that down .
What the hell are you doing out there ?
DELIA : Listen to me . No ! - Jesus .
Why are you doing this to me ? This is my art and it is dangerous .
Do you think I want to die like this ?
[ CAR HORN HONKS ]
- No , no . - Hi . How are you ?
That little girl saw us .
- Honey , nobody can see us . - But she did .
- What happened to the previous owners ? - They drowned .
Yes , they were family . I was devastated .
- Here , take that . - Is this the key to the attic ?
That 's a skeleton key . That key will open any door in the house .
Give that to your father .
And you might mention that I single-handedly decorated that house .
In case he needs any advice in that arena , have him come see me .
[ STAIRCASE CREAKING ]
Don 't worry . I locked the door .
[ LOCK RATTLING ]
[ STATIC ON TV ]
[ BETELGEUSE LAUGHING ]
Having trouble with the living ? You tired of having your home violated ?
You want to get rid of them pesky living critters ?
Well , come on down and see me , folks , I 'm the afterlife 's leading bio-exorcist .
Yes , sirree . Come on down here and I want to tell you , I 'll do anything .
I 'll scare them real bad . The point is , folks , I 'm gonna do anything to get your business .
Hell , I 'll possess myself if I gotta .
Wow ! Yo , I got demons running all through me .
All through me . Come on down here and see it .
And hey , if you act now , you get a free demon possession with every exorcism .
You can 't beat that , can you ?
And bring the little pards down .
Hell , we got plenty of snakes and lizards for them to play with . No problem at all .
So say it once , say it twice , third time 's the charm . And remember :
I 'll eat anything you want me to eat Swallow anything you want me to swallow .
So come on down , I 'll chew on the dog
[ HOWLS ]
We need some help . I read something in this book this morning about emergencies .
All right , here it is . " In case of emergency , draw a door . "
" Draw a door " ? I don 't know why we keep looking in that stupid book .
Hey , maybe we should try that " Beetle " guy .
Oh .
You didn 't actually think that was gonna work , did you ?
Aha !
" Knock three times . "
[ RUMBLING ]
Blugh .
[ WHISTLES ]
Birdies .
Get it .
LYDIA : Dad .
- Can 't you see I 'm relaxing in here ? - Well , I wanna tell you what I saw .
What is the point of my coming up here if you people won 't let me relax ?
Pumpkin , sweetheart
go help your mother .
Maybe you can relax in a haunted house , but I can 't .
Hmm .
Nice building . Bad roof . Good parking .
[ GASPS ]
- Adam ? - This way , honey .
You don 't have an appointment , do you ?
Well , we didn 't know how to make one .
- Appointment for what ? - What do you want ?
- We need some help . - Ha ! Already ?
You just bit the big one two months ago and you want help .
What does that have to do with anything ?
You 're gonna use up all your help vouchers : D-90s .
You spend 125 years on Earth actually in that house
during which you get only three class-one D-90 intercessions with Juno .
You probably haven 't even read through the manual completely yet .
You 'll have to wait if you don 't have an appointment .
- An appointment with whom ? - For Juno , your caseworker .
Number 54,000,601 . Ferndock .
- Want a cigarette ? - Uh , no , thank you .
Trying to cut down myself .
Adam , is this what happens when you die ?
This is what happens when you die .
That is what happens when he dies . And that is what happens when they die .
It 's all very personal . And I 'll tell you something .
If I knew then what I know now , I wouldn 't have had my little accident .
[ CHUCKLING ]
Maitland . Party of two .
Take the handbook and go to the sixth door .
Oh , we forgot our handbook .
[ MUTTERING ]
Come on .
WOMAN : [ OVER PA ] All new arrivals , report to Waiting Room Number 8 .
Flight 409 is arriving at Gate 3 .
How do I look ? There are no mirrors on this side .
- Fine . You look fine . - Yeah ?
- Fine . - Thanks . I 've been feeling a little flat .
[ LAUGHING ]
WOMAN : [ OVER PA ] Will the Peterson party report to Door Number 9 ?
Peterson party , please report to Door Number 9 .
All new arrivals , report to Waiting Room Number 8 .
A hundred and 25 years . I can 't believe this .
I can 't believe they didn 't tell us .
[ GHOSTS MOANING ]
Oh , Adam , what is this ?
That 's the Lost Souls ' Room .
A room for ghosts that have been exorcised .
Poor devils .
That 's death for the dead .
It 's all in the handbook .
Keep moving .
Five .
This is the sixth door .
Boy , oh , boy , this place just gets weirder and weirder .
Barbara .
We 're home .
Look at this place . Everything 's different .
All our furniture 's gone .
How long do you suppose we were waiting there ?
Three months .
I 'd almost given up on you . I was about to leave .
I do have other clients .
- Are you Juno , our caseworker ? - Yes .
I evaluate individual cases and determine
if help is needed , deserved and available .
- Are you available ? - No .
- What 's wrong ? - We 're very unhappy .
What did you expect ? You 're dead .
We want to get rid of the people who moved in here .
Barbara and I worked very hard on this house .
We probably wouldn 't mind sharing the house with people who were ...
- More like you used to be . - Yes .
But these people ...
Things seem pretty quiet here .
You should thank God you didn 't die in Italy .
The Deetzes .
- Okay , have you been studying the manual ? - Well , we tried .
The intermediate interface chapter on haunting says it all .
Get them out yourselves . It 's your house .
Haunted houses aren 't easy to come by .
- Well , we don 't quite get it . - I heard .
Tore your faces right off .
It doesn 't do any good to pull your heads off in front of people
if they can 't see you .
- We should start more simply ? - Start simply .
Do what you know . Use your talents . Practice .
You should have been studying those lessons since day one .
[ WATCH BEEPING ]
- Ooh . I 've got to go . - What about that guy in the flyer , Betel ... ?
Shh !
Don 't even say his name . You don 't want his help .
- Well ... - We might .
No , you don 't . He does not work well with others .
What do you mean ?
I didn 't want to bring it up .
But rather than have you stumble onto it and make another mistake , I 'll tell you .
He was my assistant .
But he was a troublemaker . He went out on his own
as a freelance bio-exorcist .
Claimed he could get rid of the living . Got into more trouble .
[ SIGHS ]
In fact , I believe he 's been sleazing around your cemetery lately .
The only way he can be brought back
is by calling his name three times .
But I strongly suggest
that you remove the Deetzes yourselves .
Well , how do we contact you if we need you again ?
Oh , Adam , that guy 's in our cemetery .
She 's right , honey . We just have to keep this simple . We can do this . Come on .
[ FLY BUZZING ]
BETELGEUSE : Hey , you . Hey , come here .
Hungry ?
Come on . Hey , come here .
I got something good for you . Come on . Come on over .
We 'll have a little bite , you 'll have something to nosh .
[ LAUGHS ]
- Come here . FLY : Help me . Help me . Help me .
[ BETELGEUSE BELCHES ]
Maxie , have I not always made you money ? I think that 's the only real question here .
Well , Charles , nobody made me money like you .
I mean , before your nerves went , you were a demon .
It 's just that Winter River , Connecticut is , if you 'll forgive me , nowhere .
Why would I wanna invest that kind of money in an old building ...
- ... way the hell up there ? - It 's not a building . That 's the beauty of it .
These people don 't know the value of their property . I can buy the whole town .
Oh , then we own a whole town in the middle of nowhere .
Max , you 've got to come up here and see .
CHARLES : [ OVER PHONE ] And , uh , bring Sarah .
Yeah , all right , Charles . It 's just that I am kind of busy here .
[ MOANING NEARBY ]
Uh , just a minute , Maxie .
Now , listen . Enough of this talk about visiting , okay ? I gotta go .
MAXIE : [ OVER PHONE ] You take it easy up there , big fellow .
- Goodbye . - Uh , Max , wait , wait , wait .
[ DIAL TONE OVER PHONE ]
Putz .
[ MOANING NEARBY ]
Jeez , Lydia , is Connecticut so boring ? I had Maxie Dean on the phone , honey .
Dad 's found a way of making some money while I relax , so would you scram ?
Your mother 's gonna kill you when she sees you cut holes in her $ 300 sheets .
This is so corny . Is this what we 've been reduced to ? Sheets ?
ADAM : Think of them as death shrouds .
And the moaning is important . Really moan .
[ BOTH MOANING ]
[ ADAM AND BARBARA MOANING NEARBY ]
[ SIGHS ]
God , how can he stand that woman ?
Cut it out . I 'm a child , for God 's sakes .
BARBARA : I feel so stupid . ADAM : It 's not stupid . We 're ghosts .
Do you want to spend the next 125 years having breakfast with this woman ?
Moan louder .
[ BOTH MOANING LOUDLY ]
[ TV CLICKS OFF ]
ADAM : Oh , God .
[ ADAM SIGHS ]
[ CAMERA CLICKING AND WHIRRING ]
Sick . Sexual perversion .
If you guys are gonna do that weird sexual stuff , do it in your own bedroom .
No feet .
Are you the guys hiding out in the attic ?
ADAM : [ MOANING ] We 're ghosts .
BARBARA : Whoo !
- What do you look like under there ? ADAM : Aren 't you scared ?
I 'm not scared of sheets . Are you gross under there ?
Are you Night of the Living Dead under there ?
Like all bloody veins and pus ?
- Night of the what ? - Living Dead . It 's a movie .
If I had seen a ghost at your age , I would have been scared out of my wits .
You 're not gross . Why are you wearing sheets ?
We 're practicing .
- You can see us without the sheets ? - Of course I can see you .
Well , how is it that you see us and nobody else can ?
Well , I read through that Handbook for the Recently Deceased .
It says , " Live people ignore the strange and unusual . "
I myself am strange and unusual .
You look like a regular girl to me .
ADAM : You read our book ? - Yeah .
- You could follow it ? - Yeah . Why were you in Delia 's bedroom ?
- We were trying to scare your mother . - Stepmother .
Anyway , you can 't scare her . She 's sleeping with Prince Valium tonight .
You did this ? You carved all these little houses and things ?
Mm-hm .
And this used to be your house .
Why do you want to scare everybody ?
Well , we wanted to frighten you so you would move out .
[ LAUGHS ]
You don 't know the Deetzes very well .
My father bought this place . He never walks away from equity .
- Why don 't you leave ? - We can 't .
We haven 't left the house since the funeral .
Funeral .
God . You guys really are dead .
This is amazing .
CHARLES : Lydia .
- I better go . - Wait .
- Don 't tell your parents that we 're up here . - Unless you think it 'll frighten them away .
You tell them that we are horrible
desperate , ghoulish creatures who will stop at nothing to get our house back .
What if this is a dream ? Can you guys do any tricks to prove I 'm not dreaming ?
Well , if you are real ghosts , you guys better get another routine because those sheets
they don 't work .
DELIA : Ghosts .
You 're telling me we have ghosts in this house .
Those pictures are of ghosts . Are they ?
Ghosts .
Lydia , I am giving a dinner party tonight for seven people .
My agent , Bernard , is bringing a woman who writes for Art in America .
In fact , no one dining here this evening has not been in Vanity Fair except you .
I told them you were too mean to be afraid .
Don 't you dare speak to others about me .
Being embarrassed in front of the few people who will set foot in here scares me .
So let 's play family just for tonight , hmm ?
Lydia 's trying , but they don 't believe her .
She 's got photos , Barbara .
Adam , you had a photo of Bigfoot .
My photo of Bigfoot is a different story .
Anyhow , we 've gotta get some help here .
We 've gotta contact this guy , Betelmeyer , or something .
Adam .
Look .
It 's him . Betelgeuse .
Betelgeuse .
Go ahead , Barbara , say it .
What happened ?
I think we 're in the model .
Hey , look at that .
Well , where is he ? What do we do ?
Looks like we dig , Barbara .
[ ADAM GRUNTS ]
Oh , it 's about time .
- I say we open it . - Maybe we should knock first .
Yeah .
Adam . Babs .
Boy , do you know how to pick them . Is this relationship solid ? Do I have a shot at her ?
- Excuse me . - Sure . Am I overstepping my bounds ?
Just tell me . Come on . Know what 's beautiful about this ?
You two kids picked me . You didn 't have to , but you picked me .
It makes me want to kiss you guys . Come on , give me one .
- No ! - I beg your pardon .
All right , let 's get down to business .
I 've got a card here somewhere . Here . Who do I have to kill ?
Here , hold that for me , will you ?
[ BARBARA SCREAMS ]
- There you go . - You don 't have to kill anybody .
Ah , possession . Good .
BETELGEUSE : Learn to throw your voice . Fool your friends . Fun at parties .
[ IN NORMAL VOICE ] No . We just wanna get some people out of our house .
I understand . Well , look , in order to do that , I 'm gonna have to get to know you guys .
We 've got to get closer . Move in with you for a while .
Get to be real pals . You know what I 'm saying ? In ...
[ SNORTS ]
Save that guy for later , huh ?
My wife and I would like to ask a couple of questions .
- Sure , sure , sure . Go ahead . Shoot . - For instance , what are your qualifications ?
[ IN
CULTURED VOICE ] Ah . Well , I attended Juilliard .
I 'm a graduate of the Harvard Business School .
I lived through the Black Plague . And I had a pretty good time during that .
[ IN NORMAL VOICE ] I 've seen The Exorcist about 167 times
and it keeps getting funnier every single time I see it .
Not to mention the fact that you 're talking to a dead guy .
Now , what do you think ? You think I 'm qualified ?
What I mean is , can you be scary ?
Oh ! Oh .
I know what you 're asking me . Can I be scary ?
What do you think of this ?
[ BOTH SCREAM ]
You like it ?
- Will you excuse us , please ? - Sure . Talk amongst yourself .
- Adam , let 's go . - I know , but I think he can be useful later .
BARBARA : We can work something out . - Oh , yeah .
BARBARA : Hey , hey , hey . ADAM : Excuse me .
- What ? - Excuse me . We are leaving now .
Oh , come on . Don 't go yet .
Hey , guy , come on . We 're simpatico here .
Look at us , huh ? We even shop at the same store .
Hey , hermano .
Yeah , there you go .
Hey , come on . We 're like peas in a pod , the three of us . Let 's face it .
You want somebody out of the house . I want to get somebody out of your house .
Look . We 've been to Saturn . Hey , I 've been to Saturn .
Whoa . Sandworms .
You hate them , right ? I hate them myself .
Come on , kids , what do I have to do to strike a deal with you two , huh ?
[ SCREAMING ]
- Don 't you hate it when that happens ? - Let 's go .
Wait a minute . Just come up for a while . We 'll talk inside . Come on . Come on .
BARBARA : I 'm not staying here . - The place is a mess .
- We have to get out of here . - I 'll fix you something to eat .
Home . Home . Home .
- Barbara , how did you do that ? - Hope you like Italian .
Where 'd you go ? Hey , come on . Hey , where 'd you go ?
Hey . Come on . You 've got to work with me here .
I 'm just trying to cut a deal . What do you want me to do ?
Where are you ?
You bunch of losers !
You 're working with a professional here .
Nice fucking model .
[ HONKING ]
BARBARA : See , we can do this stuff on our own .
Besides , I 'm not exposing that little girl to that pervert down there .
Barbara , we did call him , and he seemed awfully pissed off .
I don 't care . I 've changed my mind .
Listen , I think we can scare them off ourselves , tonight .
I have an idea .
I think what you did with the place is wonderful .
[
WHISPERING ] Not me . Them .
- So ? - Oh . Um ...
[ BERNARD CLEARS THROAT ]
Uh ...
You like them .
I just hope it wasn 't yet another of your dreary suicide attempts .
You know what they say about people who commit suicide ?
In the afterlife , they become civil servants .
[ CHUCKLES ]
Otho , I didn 't realize you were into the supernatural .
Well , of course . You remember .
After my stint with The Living Theatre
I was one of New York City 's leading paranormal researchers
until the bottom dropped out in ' 72 .
Paranormal ? Is that what they 're calling your kind these days ?
Don 't mind her . She 's still upset because somebody dropped a house on her sister .
Well , this looks really good .
I saw some ghosts .
- It 's a little private joke Lydia and I share . - It 's not a joke .
Yes , it is . Just today she tried to convince me that this house is haunted .
Kids . You know , I love them .
- By ghosts ? - In designer sheets , no less .
I 'd like to propose a toast to our intrepid friends
who braved the expressway and two dozen tollbooths to be with us .
May your buildings go condo .
Now , Lydia , favor us about your ghosts .
No . I am sick of that subject .
Oh , Delia , lighten up .
I would rather talk about ...
[ SINGING " DAY-O " IN HARRY BELAFONTE 'S VOICE ]
That 's cute , Delia .
[ CHUCKLES ]
Otho , are you doing this ?
[ ALL SINGING ]
[ ALL SCREAMING ]
We did it .
Let 's watch them scatter .
Any minute now they 're gonna come running out of that door screaming .
Any minute now .
[ KNOCKING ON DOOR ]
LYDIA : It 's me , Lydia .
They want you to come downstairs .
Delia says you can wear any sheets you want .
It was like being in an amusement park .
[
LAUGHING ] Wham !
- I didn 't even know I could do the Calypso . - Who has more fun than us ?
We 're dealing with Tracy and Hepburn here .
A very sophisticated pair . I mean , they even appear in sheets .
[ LAUGHS ]
Charles , what I wanna know is why didn 't you tell us about this before ?
Well , we 're not even sure we want our secret out .
I mean , everyone 's gonna want them for their parties , ha , ha .
People will pay big money for this , Grace .
The Enquirer is offering $ 50,000 for proof of life after death .
DELIA : Fifty thousand ?
This is it , Charles . You can get Maxie Dean up here now .
- You think so ? - Sarah loves the supernatural .
She 'll have him sprint up here in his helicopter
if you can produce ghosts for her .
Oh , Charles .
I should remind you all that I am Delia 's agent .
I have consistently lost money on her work for years .
If anything actually happened here , I shall handle it .
But not until I 've seen some real proof .
- But , Bernard , what about this table ? - What just happened , what was that ?
And what money ? Don 't you believe in my work ?
CHARLES : Uh-uh-uh !
Here 's Lydia .
- Well ? - They don 't want to come down .
DELIA : Charles .
Why not ?
I think the reason is that they were trying to scare you away , and you didn 't get scared .
Please , they 're dead . It 's a little late to be neurotic .
All right .
This was not a hallucination . This was real .
We all just experienced a very super-powerful paranormal experience and it was real .
Delia , you are a flake . You have always been a flake .
If you insist on frightening people , do it with your sculpture .
CHARLES : Drive carefully .
- I 'm dead . - Where do they hide out ?
- The attic . - The attic 's locked .
They 're ghosts , Dad . They can do what they want .
Yeah , they do whatever they want . Lydia , you take us up there right now .
Fabulous . Otho Fenlock 's " Locked Door Ghosts . "
Probably committed suicide up there .
- I 'm totally enchanted . DELIA : They 're in there ?
- They must live like animals . - It 's locked . How did they get in ?
Open this door , you dead people , or we 'll bust it down
and drag you out by the ropes you hanged yourself with .
- They didn 't commit suicide . - It doesn 't matter .
I have a chance to teach you something . Take the upper hand in all situations
or people , whether dead or alive , will walk all over you .
Open up !
So where are they ?
Listen , you guys , these ghosts are really nice people .
I think we scared them away , so let 's just leave them alone , all right ?
It 's the whole damn town .
I have never been so embarrassed . They haven 't gone for good , have they ?
Hmm .
CHARLES : Beep , beep . - Dad , don 't . Mom , let 's just go .
No ghosts here .
Come on . If they are in here , I don 't want to scare them away .
Well , we 're leaving now . You can go about your business .
CHARLES : What are we doing ? DELIA : Quick , quick , quick .
[ BETELGEUSE LAUGHING ]
Oh , boy . You guys are really a couple of spooksters , aren 't you ?
Now , let 's turn on the juice and see what shakes loose .
Otho , you get Maxie on the phone . We 've really got something here .
We can turn this place into the world 's leading supernatural research center .
An amusement park . I 'll do a presentation . Lydia will bring the ghosts .
I can 't bring the ghosts , Dad . They 're not here .
- Otho , can 't you do something ? - Perhaps . If I 'm properly motivated .
Just what type of motivation do you require , Otho ?
LYDIA : Why don 't you leave them alone ? They didn 't do anything to you .
[ RATTLING ]
[ DELIA GASPS ]
[
HISSING ] Hi .
[ SCREAMS ]
[ CHUCKLING ]
Whoa !
[ BETELGEUSE LAUGHS ]
We 've come for your daughter , Chuck .
Stop . Stop .
Yeah .
- Betelgeuse , Betelgeuse , Betelgeuse . - Oh , no .
Why are you doing this ?
Leave me alone , all of you .
Great choice we got here . We spend the next century
either hanging out the window or doing parlor tricks .
Maybe they 'll leave now . That snake was a nasty customer .
- Well , he could 've hurt somebody . - But he didn 't .
We 've got them right where we want them .
You bunch of losers . How dare you interrupt a professional while he 's working .
I 'm not fond of Charles Deetz , but you could 've killed him .
Hey , I 'm just doing my job . Besides , I thought we had a deal .
Hey , it 's okay . You know why ?
I don 't wanna do business with you deadbeats anyway , thank you .
The only one I think I can deal with is Edgar Allan Poe 's daughter .
- I think she understands me . - You leave her alone , you ...
Ow !
Go ahead , make my millennium .
[ LAUGHING ]
Yeah .
I 'm feeling a little , uh , ooh , anxious , if you know what I mean .
It 's been about 600 years , after all .
I wonder where a guy , an everyday Joe like myself
can find a little action .
WOMAN : Hi .
Yeah .
WOMAN : Come on . Come on in .
Oh , yeah . Here I come , baby .
Oh , yeah . Hey , Adam , nice move .
- Adam , why did you build that ? - I didn 't .
WOMAN : [ OVER PA ] All new arrivals report to Waiting Room Number 8 .
Will you guys shut up and leave me alone ?
I 've got all this paperwork to do .
You two , come in here . Sit down .
Get in here , both of you .
The whorehouse was my idea . I want Betelgeuse out of the picture .
You two have really screwed up .
I received word you allowed yourselves to be photographed .
And you let Betelgeuse out and didn 't put him back .
And you let Otho get hold of the handbook .
The handbook ? When ?
Never trust the living .
We cannot have a routine haunting like yours
provide proof that there is existence beyond death .
- Coach . Coach , where 's the men 's room ? FOOTBALL PLAYER : Yeah .
I 'm not your coach . He survived .
FOOTBALL PLAYER : Wait , coach , let me get something straight .
- What 's our curfew around here ? - Will you get out of here ?
Go on , get downstairs . " Men 's room . "
Are you kidding ? Can 't you read signs ?
I 'll be right back .
FOOTBALL PLAYER : Come on . Get out of my way .
Maybe this was all a bad idea .
I didn 't say anything .
Oh , who are we kidding , Charles ? You 've never had a bad idea .
Yeah ?
Yeah , this could all work out .
Home .
Though
I 'm not sure that this is the right environment for Lydia .
- Snakes . Ghosts . - Shrimp .
You family types .
You 've got other things to worry about . Maxie Dean 's coming up here tonight .
You 've got to figure out a way to sell these ghosts . I can only do so much .
What are you gonna do , Otho ? Viciously rearrange their environment ?
I know just as much about the supernatural as I do about interior design .
" I am ... "
" ... alone . "
" ... utterly ... "
" By the time ... "
" ... you read this ... "
" ... I will ... "
" ... be gone ... "
" ... having jumped ... "
" Having plummeted ... "
" ... off ... "
" ... the Winter River Bridge . "
So I don 't care what it takes .
You get the Deetzes out of there now .
WOMAN : [ OVER PA ] Flight 409 arriving . - Whoa , wait a minute .
WOMAN : [ OVER PA ] Flight 409 is arriving . - What are you going to do ?
To scare them .
I want to make sure it 's not some silly parlor trick .
I 'll go first , honey .
[ ADAM GRUNTS ]
[ SQUISHING ]
Not bad . Not bad . Now you .
Go ahead .
Okay , you look great .
Now , go clean house and don 't forget the photographs and the damned handbook .
WOMAN : [ OVER PA ] Please report to Door Number 9 .
All new arrivals , report to Waiting Room Number 8 .
- Coach ? JUNO : What ?
I don 't think we survived that crash .
How did you guess ?
Mr. and Mrs. Maitland ?
Hello ?
- Where are you ? BETELGEUSE : Dead .
Dead , dead , deadski .
Of course they 're dead . They 're ghosts .
No , I mean they 're gone . Split . Out of here . Afterlife kids .
- Deceased . - Are you a ghost too ?
I 'm the ghost with the most , babe .
You know , you look like somebody I can relate to .
Maybe you could help me get out of here , you know , because
I gotta tell you , this , uh , death thing ...
[ CRUNCHING ]
It 's just too creepy .
See , here 's my problem .
I got these friends on the outside that I said I 'd meet .
You know , I have to be there in person , you know .
So I was just wondering , could you help me get out of here ?
I wanna get in .
Why ?
Well , you know
hey , you 've probably got your reasons , but I can 't do anything from over here .
If you could get me out , over there , then maybe we could talk or something .
But , you know , in order to do that you 've gotta say my name three times .
What 's your name ?
- Well , uh , I can 't tell you . - Why not ?
Because if I tell you , you 'll tell your friends , they 're calling me on the horn all the time .
I 've gotta show up at shopping centers for openings , sign autographs , shit like that .
And it makes my life a hell , okay ? A living hell .
But maybe if you have a pen , maybe we can ... I know . You ever play charades ?
- Yeah . - Good . Good .
Ahh , here we go then . Ready ?
- Um , two words . - Right .
First word , two syllables .
Look .
You know , just turn around .
I don 't know what your signal means .
Turn around and look behind you .
Hi . How are you ?
- Beetle . - Got it . Okay , now , two .
Breakfast ? Orange ? Orange beetle ?
Beetle fruit ?
Beetle breakfast ?
Beetle drink ?
Beetle ...
Beetle juice ?
- Yes . That 's it . - Your name 's Betelgeuse ?
You said it twice . Just say it once more . Come on .
It was you , wasn 't it ?
- Wha ... ? Me ? - The snake .
No , what snake ? You kids and your imagination .
Just say it .
No .
I want to talk to Barbara .
No , you don 't need to talk to Barbara . Just say it .
Oh , Adam , I can 't go through with it . I like that little girl .
But , Barbara , honey , it 's too late . We have to go through with this .
No , we don 't . I mean , can 't we rebel or something ?
[ ADAM SIGHS ]
Barbara .
Adam , I want to be with Lydia .
Come on . Just say it .
ADAM : No ! BARBARA : No ! Lydia , don 't say it .
You . Say it .
It 's okay . It 's okay . It 's us . What 's going on ?
- Betel ... - Shh !
He told me that if I let him out he would take me to the other side to find you .
No , Lydia , we 're dead .
- I wanna be dead too . - No .
Lydia
being dead really doesn 't make things any easier .
Listen to her on this , Lydia . This is something we know a lot about .
And you can come up here and visit us anytime you want .
I have a feeling things are going to be a little better around here from now on .
[ GRUNTING ]
What do you mean , better ?
Well , we 've decided that we 're going to invite you and your family to stay .
That 's right , Lydia .
OTHO : Why can 't we bring Maxie up here ? - You 've got a stake in this too .
This is a presentation . It requires a sense of occasion , a sense of style .
- It 's so big . How will we get it out ? - It 's sectional .
- Wait , there are plugs . - Careful .
Okay , go .
- What 's going on ? - I don 't know . I 'll go find out .
Be careful .
We 've got Ed Cornwall to head the wax museum
dedicated to 50 great moments of the paranormal here in Thanksgiving Park .
Now , you must remember Ed , Maxie .
He 's the genius who gave us the talking Marcel Marceau statue . It was a sensation .
And D-CON is on its knees to sponsor the insect zoo
here in the old hardware store .
We can 't lose .
Lydia , you finally decided to join us .
Honey , I just , uh , finished the initial presentation .
And now I think it 's time to have a stretch
and to invite our friends to meet your friends , okay ?
Are they here yet ?
Charles , we 're here to see some ghosts .
They 're not here anymore .
Every time she says that , the paint peels
and , uh , some wild creature tries to kill us .
But we have these pictures , Lydia .
No , really . They said they might come back and we could all live here
if you agreed not to tease them or make them do stupid tricks .
She has such a tendency to overreact .
Don 't worry , we 're not relying on her . We have Otho .
- Are they still here , Otho ? - Otho , are they still here ?
Oh , they 're still here . They 're just hiding out .
Probably feel guilty about what they did to me .
They 're sorry they didn 't kill you .
Well , I don 't know from guilt . I just wanna see them .
Otho , can you do it ?
- It 'll be tricky , but I think I can handle it . - No .
Wait . What am I worried about ? Otho , you can 't even change a tire .
I 'll be needing something personal of theirs .
You 'll have to go to the Goodwill .
Excuse me .
The wedding clothes .
The words :
[ CHANTING ] Hands vermilion
Start of five
Bright cotillion
Raven 's dive
Nightshade 's promise
Spirits strive
To the living Let now the dead come alive
Barbara ?
[ CHANTING ] As sudden thunder pierces night
As magic wonder mad affright
Rives asunder man 's delight
Our ghost , our corpse
And we rise to be
Oh , no .
[ MOUTHS ] Help .
Barbara ?
- Stop it . - Shh !
LYDIA : No .
OTHO : [
CHANTING ] As flies the lizard
Serpent fell
As goblin vizard at the spell
The buried , dead and slain rise again
[ MOUTHS ] Barbara ?
What 's happening to them ?
I don 't know .
They 're dying .
No , they 're not . They 're already dead . They can 't feel a thing .
- That 's not true . Look at them . CHARLES : All right , that 's enough now .
Can you stop this ?
Otho .
It 's too late , Charles . I 'm sorry .
Where are you ? Help them , please .
Sure , I can help them . But you 've gotta help me .
- What ? - Look , I 'm what you call an illegal alien .
I want out for good . In order for me to do that , hey , I gotta get married .
Hey , these aren 't my rules . Come to think of it , I don 't have any rules .
Come on . Come on .
Think of it as a marriage of inconvenience . Okay ? We both get something . I get out .
You get to say you 're hitched with the most eligible bachelor since Valentino .
- We 're even , babe . - Okay , just help them .
Sure .
Betelgeuse .
It 's showtime .
Attention , Kmart shoppers .
[ GASPS ]
[ LAUGHS ]
Well , I 'm back . I feel real good about myself . You know what I mean ? So
without further delay
welcome to Winter River Museum of Natural Greed .
A monument to the bored businessman .
Come on , a little closer . Step right up . Test your strength .
[ LAUGHS ]
BETELGEUSE : Thank you .
Thank you .
That is why I won 't do two shows a night anymore , babe .
I won 't . I won 't do them .
Well , what have we got here tonight , kids ?
Well , we 've got the , uh , Maitlands .
I think they 've had enough exercise for tonight .
Not so fast , Round Boy . We 're gonna have some laughs .
[ CACKLES ]
Otho .
[ SCREAMS ]
[ BETELGEUSE CHUCKLES ]
Come on , come on , come on .
Yeah .
Mom , Dad :
I just want you two to know you 're welcome in our house
anytime you want to come over .
In the meantime , the dowry 's on me , Dad .
Well , the Maitlands are taken care of .
Everything seems to be pretty much back to normal , I think .
Shall we ?
Called the caterer . He 's got a great band .
We 're gonna need witnesses . Would you ?
[ SCREAMING ]
Come on . Let 's go . Let 's get on with the ceremony .
Do you , Betel ...
Aah ! Uh-uh !
- Nobody says the " B " word . Come on . PREACHER : Do you take this woman
to be your wedded wife ?
Oh , jeez , I don 't know . I mean , it 's kind of a big decision .
I always said if I ever did it , I was gonna do it once and that was it .
Sure . Yeah . Go ahead .
And you , do you , Lydia , take this man ...
No . Betel ...
She 's a little bit nervous . Uh , maybe I should answer for her , okay ?
[ IN LYDIA 'S VOICE ] I 'm Lydia and I 'm of sound mind .
The man next to me is the one I want . You asked me . I 'm answering .
Yes , I love that man of mine .
- [ IN NORMAL VOICE ] Come on . PREACHER : Then by the ...
Betel ...
Come on . Come on .
Betelgeu ...
Hey . Hey . Hey .
Scram .
Come on .
Take a hike .
PREACHER : May we continue with the ceremony ?
[ PREACHER CLEARS THROAT ]
- Then by ... - Betelgeuse .
- Betelgeuse . - Oh , gee .
Strike .
Come on , let 's get rolling now , rev.
Then by the authority vested in me ...
- The ring , please . - The ring . Oh , no .
Jewelry store . Here .
That 's not it .
You know I got it , honey .
[ SANDWORM GROWLING ]
Here it is . Here you go .
I 'm telling you , honey , she meant nothing to me . Nothing at all .
- I now pronounce you ... - Yeah , yeah , come on .
Man and ...
Ow !
[ BOTH SCREAMING ]
[ SCREAMS ]
[ CHUCKLES ]
GIRL : Bye . LYDIA : Bye .
Bye .
- Bye , you guys . - Bye .
- What time is it , honey ? - It 's about 3 : 30 , I guess .
Give or take a year .
Hello ?
Well ?
Did you get the paints ?
Yes . And I took pictures of the new town hall for you too .
BARBARA : How 'd you do on that Science test ?
It was gross . They wanted me to dissect a frog .
I told them no way . I said it was against my religion . So I got a C.
And how about the Math test ?
You have got to be kidding me . We spent the whole week studying for that test .
I got an A.
So can I ?
Well , I don 't know . Got a C on the Science test .
Adam , don 't tease her . You never got on A in Science ...
Come on .
Well
I suppose .
[ HARRY BELAFONTE 'S " JUMP IN THE LINE " PLAYING ]
This thing reads like stereo instructions .
Sounds like Lydia got an A on the Math test . Jeez !
He likes it .
[ SINGING " JUMP IN THE LINE " IN HARRY BELAFONTE 'S VOICE ]
Hey !
Sorry . Didn 't see you sitting there .
Women .
I don 't know what her problem is .
Normally , chicks ...
[ DINGS ]
[ SIGHS ]
Pardon me . Did you do that ?
That 's very nice work . Let me ask , how do you get them so sm ... ?
Hey , there goes Elvis . Yo , King .
Well , looks like I 'm next .
Good thing too . I gotta do a photo shoot for GQ in about an hour and a half .
They 've been after me for months . Doing some kind of underwear deal , I don 't know ...
Hey , what are you doing ? Stop it . You 're messing up my hair .
[ IN
HIGH-PITCHED VOICE ] Come on ! Whoa ! Whoa ! Stop it !
Whoa !
Hey , this might be a good look for me .
[ ALL SINGING ]
[ ENGLISH SDH ]